<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools">
    <string name="app_name">DietChartFinal</string>

    <string name="appeldetails"> Apples are among the world’s most popular fruits.They grow on the apple tree (Malus domestica),originally from Central Asia. Apples are high infiber, vitamin C, and various antioxidants. They are also very filling, considering their low calorie count. Usually eaten raw, apples can also be used in various recipes, juices, and drinks. Various types abound, with a variety of colors and sizes.</string>
    
    <string name="bananadetails">Bananas are among the most important food
crops on the planet. They come from a family of
plants called Musa that are native to Southeast
Asia and grown in many of the warmer areas of
the world. Bananas are a healthy source of
fiber, potassium, vitamin B6, vitamin C, and
various antioxidants and phytonutrients. Many
types and sizes exist. Their color usually ranges
from green to yellow, but some varieties are red.</string>

    <string name="grapes">People have cultivated grapes for thousands of
years, including several ancient civilizations that
revered them for their use in winemaking.
Grapes also make a quick and delicious snack
you can enjoy at home or on the go. You may
find them in various colors, including green, red,
black, yellow, and pink. They come in multiple
forms, too, from raisins to jellies to juice.
Seeded and seedless varieties also exist.
Grapes offer a wealth of health benefits,
primarily due to their high nutrient and
antioxidant contents.</string>

    <string name="guavas">Guavas are tropical trees originating in Central
America. Their fruits are oval in shape with light
green or yellow skin and contain edible seeds.
What’s more, guava leaves are used as an
herbal tea and the leaf extract as a supplement.
Guava fruits are amazingly rich in antioxidants,
vitamin C, potassium, and fiber. This remarkable
nutrient content gives them many health
benefits.</string>

    <string name="litchi">The lychee (Litchi chinensis) — also known as
litchi or lichee — is a small tropical fruit from the
soapberry family. Other popular fruits in this
family include rambutan and longan.

Lychees are grown in subtropical regions
throughout the world and especially popular in
their native China, as well as Southeast Asia.

Known for their sweet and flowery flavor, they’re
typically eaten fresh and sometimes used in ice
creams or processed into juice, wine, sherbert,
and jelly.

They’re a good source of several vitamins,
minerals, and healthy antioxidants.

Lychees have an inedible, pink-red, leathery
skin, which is removed before consumption. The
flesh is white and surrounds a dark seed in the
center.

Lychees are mainly composed of water
and carbs — which make up 82% and 16.5% of
the fruit, respectively Carbs and Fibers

Besides water, lychees are mainly composed of
carbs.

The majority of the carbs in lychees comes from
sugars, which are responsible for their sweet
taste. They’re relatively low in fiber.

Vitamins and Minerals

Lychees are a decent source of several vitamins
and minerals, including:

• Vitamin C: The most abundant vitamin
in lychees. One lychee provides around
9% of the Reference Daily Intake (RDI)
for vitamin C
• Copper: Lychees are a decent source
of copper. Inadequate copper intake
may have adverse effects on heart
health
• Potassium: An essential nutrient that
may improve heart health when eaten in
sufficient amounts</string>

    <string name="pineapple">Pineapple (Ananas comosus) is an incredibly
delicious, healthy tropical fruit. It’s packed with
nutrients, antioxidants, and other helpful
compounds, such as enzymes that can protect
against inflammation and disease. It’s
commonly eaten baked, grilled, or freshly cut.

Originating in South America, it was named by
early European colonizers for its resemblance to
a pine cone.

Pineapple and its compounds are linked to
several health benefits, including improvements
in digestion, immunity, and recovery from
surgery.

Pineapples also contain trace amounts of
phosphorus, zinc, calcium, and vitamins A and
K.

As you can see, this fruit is particularly rich
in vitamin C and manganese. Vitamin C is
essential for immune health, iron absorption,
and growth and development, while manganese
offers antioxidant properties and aids in growth
and metabolism.

Antioxidants help prevent oxidation in your
body, which may help ward off inflammation that
can lead to cancer and other chronic diseases.

Pineapples also contain other micronutrients,
such as copper, thiamine, and vitamin B6, which
are essential for healthy metabolism.</string>

    <string name="jackfruit">Jackfruit may be higher in some vitamins and minerals than apples,apricots, bananas, and avocados. For example,it is rich in vitamin C and one of the few fruits that is high in B vitamins. Jackfruit also contains folate, niacin, riboflavin, potassium, and magnesium.
        Carotenoids, the pigments that give jackfruit its yellow color, are high in vitamin A. Like all antioxidants, carotenoids protect cells fromdamage and help your body work right. Theymay help prevent diseases like cancer and heart disease, as well as eye problems like cataracts and macular degeneration. As a jackfruit ripens, its carotenoid levels maygo up.</string>

    <string name="orange">Oranges are popular due to their natural
sweetness, the many different types available,
and the diversity of uses. For example, a person
can consume them in juices and marmalades,
eat them whole, or use zested peel to add a
tangy flavor to cakes and desserts.
This popular citrus fruit is particularly known for
its vitamin C content. However, oranges contain
a range of other plant compounds
and antioxidants that may
reduce inflammation and work against disease.</string>

    <string name="strawberry">Strawberries, like other berries, are rich in
vitamins, minerals, fiber, and compounds with
antioxidant and anti-inflammatory properties. As
part of a nutritious diet, they can help prevent
various conditions.
One of these health conditions is type 2
diabetes. Evidence Trusted Source suggests
this fruit lowers the post-meal increase in blood
sugar in some people with obesity or excess
weight.
     Additionally, ingredients within strawberries may
    also help protect against heart disease, stroke,
    cancer, high blood pressure, and constipation.</string>


    <string name="mango">Mangoes are sweet, creamy fruits that have
a range of possible health benefits. They
are highly popular around the world.

The mango is a tropical stone fruit and
member of the drupe family. This is a type
of plant food with a fleshy outer section that
surrounds a shell, or pit. This pit contains a
seed.

Other members of the drupe
family include olives, dates, and coconuts.

There are many different kinds of mango.
They vary in color, shape, flavor, and seed
size. Although mango skin can be green,
red, yellow, or orange, its inner flesh is
mostly golden yellow.</string>

    <string name="blackberry">Blackberries are a delicious addition to any diet.
    They are also packed with essential nutrients
    and antioxidants.

    Blackberries are native to Europe, but farmers
    grow them across the United States all year
    round. They come from brambles, which are a
    type of thorny bush.

    In this article, we look at some of the potential
    health benefits associated with eating
    blackberries, and how to include more
    blackberries in a typical diet.</string>


    <string name="watermelon">The watermelon (Citrullus lanatus) is a large,
    sweet fruit originally from southern Africa. It’s
    related to cantaloupe, zucchini, pumpkin, and
    cucumber.

    Watermelon is packed with water and nutrients,
    contains very few calories, and is exceptionally
    refreshing.

    What’s more, it’s a good dietary source of both
    citrulline and lycopene, two powerful plant
    compounds.</string>


    <string name="coconut">Coconut is the fruit of the coconut palm (Cocos
nucifera), which is commonly used for its water,
milk, oil, and tasty meat.

Coconut trees are considered the most naturally
widespread fruit tree on the planet and are
native to Southeast Asia and the islands
between the Indian and Pacific oceans .

Today, coconuts are cultivated around the globe
and have become increasingly popular for their
flavor, culinary uses, and many potential health
benefits.

This article will explore five potential benefits of
coconuts, along with some simple ways to add
them to your diet.</string>


    <string name="Potato">Potatoes are the most commonly consumed
vegetable in the United States. In 2017, it was
calculated that each person consumed 49.2
pounds of potatoes. This beloved vegetable is
easy to grow and is used in countless dishes
across the country year-round.
Health Benefits
Potatoes are a good source of fiber, which can
help you lose weight by keeping you full longer.
Fiber can help prevent heart disease by
keeping cholesterol and blood sugar levels in
check. Potatoes are also full of antioxidants that
work to prevent diseases and vitamins that help
your body function properly.
Digestive Health
The fiber found in potatoes is a special type
called “resistant starch,” which has the health
benefits of both soluble fiber and insoluble
fiber and causes less gas than other types of
fiber. You can up the amount of resistant
starch in potatoes by cooking them a day
ahead of time and cooling them in the fridge
overnight. Feel free to reheat them before you eat.</string>
    <string name="Tomato">The tomato (Solanum lycopersicum) is a
fruit from the nightshade family native to
South America.
Despite botanically being a fruit, it’s
generally eaten and prepared like a
vegetable.
Tomatoes are the major dietary source
of the antioxidant lycopene, which has
been linked to many health benefits,
including reduced risk of heart disease
and cancer.
They are also a great source of vitamin
C, potassium, folate, and vitamin K.
Usually red when mature, tomatoes can
also come in a variety of colors,
including yellow, orange, green, and
purple. What’s more, many subspecies
of tomatoes exist with different shapes
and flavor.
</string>
    <string name="onion">Onions (Allium cepa) are bulb-shaped
vegetables that grow underground.
Also known as bulb onions or common
onions, they are grown worldwide and
closely related to chives, garlic,
scallions, shallots, and leeks.
Onions may have several health
benefits, mostly due to their high content
of antioxidants and sulfur-containing
compounds.
They have antioxidant and antiinflammatory effects and have been
linked to a reduced risk of cancer, lower
blood sugar levels, and improved bone
health.
Commonly used as a flavoring or side
dish, onions are a staple food in many
cuisines. They can be baked, boiled,
grilled, fried, roasted, sautéed,
powdered, or eaten raw.
Onions vary in size, shape, and color,
but the most common types are white,
yellow, and red. The taste ranges from
mild and sweet to sharp and spicy,
depending on the variety and season.
Onions can also be consumed when
immature, before the bulb reaches full
size. They are then called scallions,
spring onions, or summer onions.
Raw onions are very low in calories, with
only 40 calories per 3.5 ounces (100
grams).
By fresh weight, they are 89% water, 9%
carbs, and 1.7% fiber, with tiny amounts
of protein and fat</string>
    <string name="Cauliflower">Cauliflower is an extremely healthy
vegetable that’s a significant source of
nutrients.
It also contains unique plant compounds
that may reduce the risk of several
diseases, including heart disease and
cancer.
Additionally, it’s weight loss friendly and
incredibly easy to add to your diet.
Cauliflower is quite high in fiber, which is
beneficial for overall health.
There are 3 grams of fiber in one cup of
cauliflower, which is 10% of your daily.
Fiber is important because it feeds the
healthy bacteria in your gut that help
reduce inflammation and promote
digestive health.
Consuming enough fiber may help
prevent digestive conditions like
constipation, diverticulitis and
inflammatory bowel disease (IBD).
Moreover, studies show that a diet high
in fiber-rich vegetables like cauliflower is
linked with a lower risk of several
illnesses, including heart disease,
cancer and diabetes</string>
    <string name="Carrot">The carrot (Daucus carota) is a root
vegetable often claimed to be the perfect
health food.
It is crunchy, tasty, and highly nutritious.
Carrots are a particularly good source of
beta carotene, fiber, vitamin K1, potassium,
and antioxidants.
They also have a number of health benefits.
They’re a weight-loss-friendly food and have
been linked to lower cholesterol levels and
improved eye health.
What’s more, their carotene antioxidants
have been linked to a reduced risk of
cancer.
Carrots are found in many colors, including
yellow, white, orange, red, and purple.
Orange carrots get their bright color from
beta carotene, an antioxidant that your body
converts into vitamin A.Carrots are a good source of several
vitamins and minerals, especially biotin,
potassium, and vitamins A (from beta
carotene), K1 (phylloquinone), and B6.</string>
    <string name="Ginger">Gingerol is the main bioactive compound in
ginger. It’s responsible for much of ginger’s
medicinal properties.
Gingerol has powerful anti-inflammatory
and antioxidant effects, according to
research. For instance, it may help
reduce oxidative stress, which is the result
of having an excess amount of free radicals
in the body.
This area of research is relatively new, but
ginger may have powerful anti-diabetic
properties.
In a 2015 study of 41 participants with type 2
diabetes, 2 grams of ginger powder per day
lowered fasting blood sugar by 12%.
It also dramatically improved hemoglobin
A1c (HbA1c), a marker for long-term blood
sugar levels. HbA1c was reduced by 10%
over a period of 12 weeks.
There was also a 28% reduction in the
Apolipoprotein B/Apolipoprotein A-I ratio and
a 23% reduction in malondialdehyde (MDA),
which is a byproduct of oxidative stress. A
high ApoB/ApoA-I ratio and high MDA levels
are both major risk factors of heart disease.
However, keep in mind that this was just one
small study. The results are incredibly
impressive, but they need to be confirmed in
larger studies before any recommendations
can be made.
In somewhat encouraging news, a 2019
literature review also concluded that ginger
significantly reduced HbA1c in people with
type 2 diabetes. However, it also found that
ginger had no effect on fasting blood sugar.</string>
    <string name="Garlic">Garlic is a plant in the Allium (onion) family.
It is closely related to onions, shallots, and
leeks.
Each segment of a garlic bulb is called a
clove. There are about 10–20 cloves in a
single bulb, give or take.
Garlic grows in many parts of the world and
is a popular ingredient in cooking, due to its
strong smell and delicious taste.
However, throughout ancient history, the
main use of garlic was for its health and
medicinal properties.
Its use was well documented by many major
civilizations, including the Egyptians,
Babylonians, Greeks, Romans, and
Chinese.
Scientists now know that most of garlic’s
health benefits are caused by sulfur
compounds formed when a garlic clove is
chopped, crushed, or chewed.
Perhaps the most well-known compound is
allicin. However, allicin is an unstable
compound that is only briefly present in
fresh garlic after it’s been cut or crushed.
Other compounds that may play a role in
garlic’s health benefits include diallyl
disulfide and s-allyl cysteine .
    The active compounds in garlic can
reduce blood pressure
Cardiovascular diseases like heart attack
and stroke are responsible for more deaths
than almost any other condition.
High blood pressure, or hypertension, is one
of the most important factors that may lead
to these diseases.
Human studies have found garlic
supplements to have a significant impact on
reducing blood pressure in people with high
blood pressure.
In one study, 600–1,500 mg of aged garlic
extract were just as effective as the drug
Atenolol at reducing blood pressure over a
24-week period.
Supplement doses must be fairly high to
have the desired effects. The amount
needed is equivalent to about four cloves of
garlic per day</string>


    <string name="chickenDetails">Chicken is rich in an array of important
    nutrients and can be an excellent addition
    to a healthy, well-rounded diet.
    Given that chicken is low in calories but
    high in protein, it may be especially
    beneficial for weight loss, if that’s a goal
    for you. Studies show that increasing your intake
    of protein may enhance feelings of
    fullness, increase weight loss, and help
    maintain lean body mass</string>
    <string name="fishDetails">Fish is packed with many nutrients that
    most people are lacking.
    This includes high-quality protein, iodine,
    and various vitamins and minerals.
    Fatty species are sometimes considered
    the healthiest. That’s because fatty fish,
    including salmon, trout, sardines, tuna,
    and mackerel, are higher in fat-based
    nutrients.
    This includes vitamin D, a fat-soluble
    nutrient that many people are lacking.</string>
    <string name="milkDetails">Milk is a nutrient-rich beverage that may
    benefit your health in several ways.
    It’s packed with important nutrients like
    calcium, phosphorus, B vitamins,
    potassium and vitamin D. Plus, it’s an
    excellent source of protein.
    Drinking milk and dairy products may
    prevent osteoporosis and bone fractures
    and even help you maintain a healthy
    weight.
    Many people are unable to digest milk or
    choose to avoid it for personal reasons.
    For those able to tolerate it, consuming
    high-quality milk and dairy products has
    been proven to provide a number of
    health benefits</string>
    <string name="eggDetails">It is true that eggs are high in cholesterol.
    In fact, a single egg contains 212 mg,
    which is over half of the recommended
    daily intake of 300 mg.
    However, it’s important to keep in mind
    that cholesterol in the diet doesn’t
    necessarily raise cholesterol in the blood.
    The liver actually produces large amounts
    of cholesterol every single day. When you
    increase your intake of dietary
    cholesterol, your liver simply produces
    less cholesterol to even it out.
    Nevertheless, the response to eating
    eggs varies between individuals.
    In 70% of people, eggs don’t raise
    cholesterol at all
    • In the other 30% (termed “hyper
    responders”), eggs can mildly
    raise total and LDL cholesterol
    However, people with genetic disorders
    like familial hypercholesterolemia or a
    gene variant called ApoE4 may want to
    limit or avoid eggs.</string>

    <string name="GreenTeaDeteils">Green tea is touted to be one of the
    healthiest beverages on the planet.
    It’s loaded with antioxidants that have
    many health benefits, which may include:
    • improved brain function
    • fat loss
    • protecting against cancer
    • lowering the risk of heart disease
    If you look at the ingredients list for
    any fat burning supplement, chances are,
    green tea will be on there.
    This is because, according to research,
    green tea can increase fat burning
    and boost metabolic rate.
    In one study involving 10 healthy men,
    taking green tea extract increased the
    number of calories burned by 4%. In
    another involving 12 healthy men, green
    tea extract increased fat oxidation by
    17%, compared with those taking a
    placebo.
    However, some studies on green tea
    don’t show any increase in metabolism,
    so the effects may depend on the
    individual and how the study was set up.
    Caffeine may also improve physical
    performance by mobilizing fatty acids
    from fat tissue and making them available
    for use as energy.</string>
    <string name="breadDeteils">Bread is a staple food in many countries
    and has been eaten worldwide for
    millennia.
    Typically prepared from a dough made of
    flour and water, bread is available in
    many varieties, including sourdough,
    sweet bread, soda bread and more.
    Despite its widespread popularity, bread
    is often characterized as unhealthy,
    harmful and fattening.
    This article examines the health impact of
    bread, telling you whether it’s good or
    bad for you.
    Compared to other foods like fruits and
    vegetables, bread is relatively low in
    essential nutrients.
    It is rather high in calories and carbs but
    low in protein, fat, fiber, vitamins and
    minerals.</string>
    <string name="muttonDeteils">Meat often makes a regular appearance in
    the diet of humans. Whether you choose
    red or white meats, meat is rich in
    protein, vitamins, and minerals. Meat can
    be sourced from various animals, the
    most popular including cow, lamb, and
    chicken.
    Recently, goat meat has started to gain
    some traction. While it’s often been
    consumed in Asian, Caribbean, and
    Middle Eastern cuisine, the demand is
    less common in western countries.
    Considered to be one of the healthiest red
    meats, lower in saturated fat and
    cholesterol, and higher in iron than other
    red or white meats.
    Goat meat has a strong, gamey flavor,
    sweeter than lamb but less sweet than
    beef. Cooking it with lots of flavor and
    spices helps complement its unique
    flavor.
    Goat meat does not have cultural or
    religious taboos that some other meats
    may have, making it suitable for most
    cultures</string>
    <string name="riceDeteils">Many health communities view white rice
    as an unhealthy option.
    It’s highly processed and missing its hull
    (the hard protective coating), bran (outer
    layer) and germ (nutrient-rich core).
    Meanwhile, brown rice only has the hull
    removed.
    For this reason, white rice lacks many
    vitamins and minerals that are present in
    brown rice.
    However, there are some instances
    where white rice is a better option than
    brown rice.
    White and brown rice are the most
    popular types of rice and have similar
    origins.
    Brown rice is simply the entire whole rice
    grain. It contains the fiber-rich bran, the
    nutrient-packed germ and the
    carbohydrate-rich endosperm.
    On the other hand, white rice is stripped
    of its bran and germ, leaving just the
    endosperm. It’s then processed to
    improve taste, extend shelf life and
    enhance cooking properties.
    White rice is considered empty carbs
    since it loses its main sources of
    nutrients.
    However, in the US and many other
    countries, white rice is typically enriched
    with added nutrients, including iron and B
    vitamins like folic acid, niacin, thiamine
    and more.
    This table shows how 3.5 ounces (100
    grams) of the different types of rice
    compare nutritionally when cooked.</string>
    <string name="darkChocolateDeteils">Dark chocolate is loaded with nutrients
    that can positively affect your health.
    Made from the seed of the cacao tree, it’s
    one of the best sources of antioxidants
    you can find.
    Studies show that dark chocolate can
    improve your health and lower the risk of
    heart disease.
    The flavanols in dark chocolate can
    stimulate the endothelium, the lining of
    arteries, to produce nitric oxide.
    One of the functions of NO is to send
    signals to the arteries to relax, which
    lowers the resistance to blood flow and
    therefore reduces blood pressure.
    Many controlled studies show that cocoa
    and dark chocolate can improve blood
    flow and lower blood pressure, though
    the effects are usually mild.
    However, one study in people with high
    blood pressure showed no effect, so take
    this with a grain of salt.
    Given the great variation between studies
    on this subject, it’s clear that more
    research is needed</string>
    <string name="pizzaDeteils">Pizza is a favorite food for many around
    the world.
    The addicting combination of delicious
    crust, sweet tomato sauce and salty
    mozzarella cheese is sure to please even
    the pickiest of eaters.
    However, it’s commonly labeled
    unhealthy, as it can be high in calories,
    sodium and carbs.</string>
    <string name="burgerDeteils">Burger meat is the rich protein
    source, especially when it comes to
    Chapps’ top notch beef. Protein
    presents your body’s source of
    energy, it builds muscle as well as
    gives structure to the cells.
    Depending on their lifestyle and diet,
    people need between 50 and 175
    grams of protein per day. And we’re
    happy to say that one delicious
    Chapps burger will provide you with
    60 grams of protein</string>


</resources>